<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Boom Beach</string>
    <string name="list">Categories</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="howtoplay">How to play</string>
    <string name="tips">Tips</string>
    <string name="strategies">Strategies</string>
    <string name="news">News</string>
    <string name="morecoolapps">More cool apps</string>
    <string name="aboutdetails">
	Boom Beach is a fun RTS style game for the iPhone and iPad that is from the same company that makes the popular Clash of Clans game. This is not the same type of strategy game as command and conquer, but it is a fun fix for mobile gamers that want to control an army in island based warfare.
You, as the commander, take care of conquering other islands to obtain more resources and free enslaved islanders from the Blackguard, the badguy of the game. At the same time you have to defend your own base and resource bases from enemy raids.
Boom Beach takes place in an island setting with in-game currency like gems, gold and diamonds which play a central role in building your defense, mounting an offense and upgrading capabilities. This is nothing new for strategy games, but Boom Beach is heavily tilted to make the player spend real world money on in-app purchases to get more gems, which can buy extra resources and speed the game up. It is still fun to play Boom Beach, but everyone who plays will be tempted to spend cash to avoid waiting between moves.
If you want to progress faster and unlock new buildings, weapons and troops without spending real money you’ll need to use these Boom Beach tips and tricks to have more fun and progress faster.

This app and its content is not affiliated with, endorsed or sponsored by Supercell. For more information see Supercell’s Fan Content Policy: www.supercell.com/fan-content-policy.
	</string>
    <string name="howtoplaydetails">
	In order to effectively defend your base you have to build structures for producing resources like Gold, Wood, Stone and Iron. With these resources you can build defensive structures like cannons and machine guns. For upgrading these structures it’s needed to upgrade your Headquarters as well. By upgrading your Headquarters you activate additional Buildings, Troops and other upgrades.
By building the Radar structure you get the ability to explore the archipelago. At this time you can visit other islands and other players that are in the area. You can attack these islands by placing your troops at landing stations on the beach and select the structures to attack. While your soldiers are attacking the structures you can fire artillery shells from the Command Ship.
By attacking other beaches you collect ‘Battle Points’, with these points you can perform Gunboat Abilities. These Gunboat Abilities can be tactical or strategical. For instance you can use Artillery Shells or Flares. The artillery shells do damage to the defending structures and with the Flares you can maneuver your soldiers over the island. These are only two of the Gunboat Abilities, there are a lot more of them. The amount of Battle Points needed for a specific ability goes up each time you use this ability in battle. Every time you destroy a structure, you get additional Battle Points.
You can conquer the island by destroying all the structures or the Headquarters. With each victory you get rewards, coins, wood and life shards.
</string>


    <string name="tipsdetails">
	It can take up to two hours to upgrade or add a building as you progress, so it is important to keep exploring and attacking while you are building. You can make new troops while building and upgrading in Boom Beach, but not new ships so keep that in mind. In addition to multitasking, make sure the last action you take before putting the game down is to start a build or an upgrade that will take a while. If you use notification you will get alerts when you can jump in and start another building or upgrade.
In the early stages of Boom Beach gold is plentiful but wood is a hot commodity. If you try to build something that you don’t have enough wood for the game will offer to sell you the supplies using Diamonds, but remember that diamonds are something you’ll need to buy with real money down the road.
Tap on a tree and hit the shovel to turn 600 gold into 300 lumber. This is a pretty fair trade-off in the early parts of the game, especially if you build more residences and free villages to keep the gold flowing.

If you upgrade your headquarters, economy, sniper towers and landing ships you’ll gain access to new crew members, better fighting capacity and faster returns on wood and gold production.
Upgrading the headquarters is a great place to start as it will unlock all of the buildings. If you start doing this early you can get up to a level 5, where things start to open up more.
Diamonds are the in game currency that does not regenerate. We’ll explain how to get some more Diamonds, but expect them to be in low supply to convince gamers to spend cash on a the free Boom Beach game.
It may not make sense to use 7 Diamonds to make a building complete instantly, but if you need to get started on something else you can often trade in 1-2 diamonds later in the build process for an instant gratification. That is a much better spending decision.
As soon as you can build a radar. This will allow you to see more of the map and open it for exploration. Once you can explore you can attack and unlock gold, wood and medals. It costs gold to unlock parts of the map, but there is always more gold in those locations.
It is tempting to rush into an attack, but if you don’t know what it looks like you may end up losing troops and wasting time and resources. Use the free scout option to see if you can take an island before wasting gold with an attack that fails or that you need to retreat from.
Building new riflemen is easy, quick and cheap, but the heavy gunners take more time, use them wisely. Eventually you will be able to direct the gunners with flares.
The Gunboat has special abilities that can aid and support your troops. It should be noted, however, that all damaging abilities and the stun ability allow for friendly fire. Additionally, improper smoking and flare usage can use troop AI against them, so the judgement of when and where to deploy these measures should always be regarded with careful execution.
The most often used are Artillery and Barrage. Both of these deal damage to the opponent\'s buildings. It is often a good idea to destroy key defenses like Rocket Launchers and Boom Cannons before deploying troops. However, this order may change based on the types of troops you plan to deploy. It should be noted that shells from both of these deal splash damage to enemy buildings; two or more buildings that touch can be damaged by one Artillery shell.
	</string>
   

   <string name="strategiesdetails">
   There are two ways to get free Boom Beach diamonds. They both take some time and in-game resources, but they are better than paying for them with real money.
Tap on the three star icon in the upper left to see achievements. Unlocking these will earn free Boom Beach diamonds.
The next way is to explore the map. Eventually you will come across a chest of free Boom Beach diamonds that will help you get to the fun parts faster.
When you start playing Boom Beach you don’t need to worry about attacks, but eventually other computer characters and players will attack you.
Start with a defense that covers the perimeter, but soon you will need to cover the center of your base so it is not left open to attackers that rush past a sniper tower.
Look at the islands you defeat and learn from their weaknesses. Multiple layers of defense with various types of weapons will serve gamers best.
Unlike traditional strategy games it is possible to move buildings later. This means as the base grows you can reorganize to keep the headquarters and other resources protected without spending gold and wood on doubling up.
Tap on a building and then drag to move it around on the map.
When possible upgrade the gunboats and landing crafts. Doing this will allow them to carry more troops or fire faster or more often. This makes attacking tougher islands easier and you’ll lose fewer troops.
Upgrading the gunboat takes away from building a new structure, but it is worth it. Same goes for the landing crafts.
When you attack an island blowing up some buildings will give you more ammo for the gunboat. You can use this as a flare to direct troops or as artillery to destroy things.
If you get it, use it. The new ammo does not carry over to the next attack. Just make sure you use it wisely or you will run out too fast.
At first a vault seems like an unnecessary expense, but once your base comes under attack you’ll regret not building a vault. Once you build the vault keep at it to upgrade the vault for more protection.
The better the vault, the more gold, lumber and supplies you will have available after losing an attack on your base. And you’ll need it to rebuild and prepare for other assaults.
   </string>
    <string name="newsdetails">
	The Dr. T, Colonel Gearheart\'s War Factory, Hammerman Strikes Back and Imitation Game events occur in a 7 day cycle.
One of these events will start at 6 a.m. each day (according to your time zone).
That event will end at 3 a.m. the following day (according to your time zone).
These times are affected by Daylight Saving Time.
Each event lasts 21 hours.
Event Cycle
Hammerman Strikes Back - Monday
Dr. T\'s Tropical Island - Tuesday
Dr. T\'s Volcano Island - Wednesday
Colonel Gearheart\'s War Factory - Thursday
Imitation Game - Friday
Dr. T\'s Tropical Island - Saturday
Dr. T\'s Volcano Island - Sunday
The cycle restarts once the Dr. T\'s Volcano Island event on Sunday has ended.
The Mega Crab is also a limited-time event, but it is not a part of the regular event cycle described above.
	</string>
</resources>
